A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Overseas Development, International Training and Research, Office Files of Cleon O. Swayzee FA610
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Overseas Development, International Training and Research, Office Files of Cleon O. Swayzee
1952-1966
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA610
2.4 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Subject Files, 1952-1966; I
  - American Centers in Near East, 1961 (Box 1)
  - American Association of Middle East Studies, 1964 (Box 1)
  - American Strategy, Study of (L65-493) -- Robert Lovett, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Area Studies -- Notes by Cleon Swayzee, Jan 1963 (Box 1)
  - Atlantic Institute -- Re: Encouraging Atlantic Studies in the United States (Jas. R. Huntley) (L64-233), 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Board of Foreign Scholarships, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Bucknell University -- Re: Expanding Non-Western Studies Program (L64-376), 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Byrnes, Robert F. -- Results of Consultantship Study -- Teaching of Russian to American Students (L8-835), 1958 (Box 1)
  - Butterfield, Victor -- Report Re: Support of General and Liberal Education in the Arab Countries of the Near East, 1953 (Box 1)
  - C -- General Files, 1959-1966 (Box 1)
  - California State Colleges -- Dr. Thomas P. Lantos (L64-506), 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Canada -- Foundation Attention to Canada Memorandum, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Canadian Universities -- General, 1962-1965 (Box 1)
  - Colorado, University of -- Memorandum from George M. Beckman Re: Colorado Situation and ITR, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Committee on the University and World Affairs (folder 1), 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - Committee on the University and World Affairs (folder 2) -- Incl. Education Reports, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Doctoral Dissertations (1955), Dissertations (1940-1950), Graduate Courses Offered in Institutions in Non-Western Areas, 1950s (Box 1)
  - Dodge, Bayard -- Statement Re: Islamic Research and Cultural Exchange, Apr 1954 (Box 1)
  - ERBs, Distribution of Doctorates by Institution and Subject, etc., 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Educational Television -- Recommended Grant Action, 1961 (Box 1)
  - European Visit -- Cleon O. Swayzee Notes/Report, May 25-Jul 10, 1964 (Box 1)
  - European Visit -- Belgium, 1964 (Box 1)
  - European Visit -- England, 1964 (Box 1)
  - European Visit -- France, 1964 (Box 1)
  - European Visit -- Germany, 1964 (Box 1)
  - European Visit -- Holland, 1964 (Box 1)
  - European Visit -- Italy, 1964 (Box 1)
  - European Visit -- Switzerland, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Evaluations of Long Term Grants, Jan 1963 (Box 1)
  - Federal Government Activities -- Foreign Area Research, Government Sponsored Research, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Foreign Area Training Fellowship Program Black Book for 1962-1963 Program, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Foreign Area Centers, 1957-1962 (Box 1)
  - G -- General Files, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Harvard University, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Harvard University -- Professor Dunlop Research on East European Economics (L64-841), 1965 (Box 1)
  - I -- General Files, 1956-1965 (Box 1)
  - Indiana University, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Indiana University -- Re: Strengthening International Studies (L65-320), 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Institute for Mediterannean Affairs, 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Iowa, State University of -- Re: International Studies (Ray L. Heffner) (L64-532), 1962-1966 (Box 1)
  - Iran -- J.B. Condliffe Report on Iran, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Iraq -- Mission Report and Memo Re: Baghdad University Library, 1952-1958 (Box 1)
  - Kansas, University of -- Study of Soviet Agricultural and Peasant Affairs (L65-50), 1965 (Box 1)
  - L -- General Files, 1960-1964 (Box 1)
  - Long-Term Support -- Area/Regional Papers, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Long-Term Support -- Background Material, Working Papers Re: International Training and Foreign Area Studies, 1959-1963 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Publications, 1957-1961 (Box 1)
  - M -- General Files, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - McCloy Committee -- General Incl. Distribution of Grant Funding, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Mosley, Philip -- Columbia University -- Re: University of Pennsylvania Proposal for Study of Elites and International Integration, 1964 (Box 1)
  - National Agencies and Foreign Area Field, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Near East -- General Information through 1960 -- Memoranda and Reports, 1955-1957 (Box 2)
  - North Carolina, University of -- International and Foreign Area Studies at the University (P. Sharp), 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Notre Dame, University of -- Latin American Studies Program and International Studies, 1963-1965 (Box 2)
  - O -- General Files, 1956-1966 (Box 2)
  - Pakistan Studies, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Princeton University -- Re: Modern European Studies, 1966 (Box 2)
  - R -- General Files, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Rand Corporation, 1957 (Box 2)
  - S -- General Files (one letter from Cleon Swayzee from Paris to John et. al), 1964 (Box 2)
  - "Small Grants", 1956 (Box 2)
  - Stephens College -- Faculty Summer Study and Development of Inter-Institutional Program in Non-Western Studies, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Swayzee, Cleon -- Trip Overseas (Spring 1955) -- Training and Research (Box 2)
  - Swayzee, Cleon -- Trip Overseas (Autumn 1957) (Box 2)
  - Swayzee, Cleon -- 1961 Trip to Near East and Europe -- Trip Report, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Undergraduate Education -- Meeting (February 18, 1965) (Box 2)
  - W -- General Files, 1964 (Box 2)
  - West European Studies -- Reports, Correspondence, Trip Itinerary, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - West European Studies -- Cleon Swayzee European Correspondence, 1964 (Box 2)
  - West European Trip -- Cleon Swayzee Notes Re: Trip to Study Education, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Wolf-Sufrin Report -- "Capital Formation and Foreign Investment in Underdeveloped Areas", 1954 (Box 2)
  - "Y" Factor Follow-Up, 1964 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- General Information, 1956-1964 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Budget Materials through 1955-1956, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Budget Materials, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Budget Materials, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Budget Materials, 1958-1959 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Budget Materials, 1959-1960 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Budget Materials, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Budget Materials, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Budget Materials, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Grant Renewals 1963-1966 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Program Planning Meeting, Oct 27, 1961 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Project Data, 1960 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Project Data, 1962 (Box 2)
  - International Training and Research -- Staff Memoranda, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Beckmann, George M. -- Correspondence, 1961-1966 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Edwards, Robert -- Memoranda, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Everton, John and Doak Barnett Trip to Asia (Autumn 1960) (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Fox, Melvin J. -- Memoranda and Report, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Harari, Maurice, 1961-1965 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Merillat, H.C.L -- Trip Overseas (Autumn 1957), 1957-1958 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Reed, Howard A., 1955-1959 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Sanders, Irwin T. -- Memoranda, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Soderlund, Dorothy, 1956-1962 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Stoke, Harold, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Thurber, Clarence E., 1956-1962 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Thurber, Clarence E. -- Trip to Southeast Asia (1957), 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Tierney, James F., 1959-1961 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Tierney, James F. -- Trip to Asia (1960), 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Weisblat, Abraham, 1954-1958 (Box 2)
  - Staff Members and Individuals -- Weisblat, Abraham -- Trip Overseas (Autumn 1957), 1957-1958 (Box 2)